fosi.org 2017-11-16

# Privacy Policy

###  Q1. What information does this Privacy Policy cover?

This Privacy Policy applies to information collected on the websites where this Privacy Policy is posted, and does not apply to any other information collected by FOSI through any other means. This Privacy Policy applies to use and sharing of information collected on and after the date that this Privacy Policy is posted.

Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to information submitted and collected online, and does not apply to information that may be collected by FOSI offline. Finally, the terms of this Privacy Policy are subject to all applicable laws.

Back to Top

###  Q2. What types of information do we collect about you?

With the exception of your Internet Protocol (IP) address, we do not require personal information to access our website. If you prefer not to disclose personal information, you may not be able to enjoy certain features of our website. Personal information is information that identifies you and may be used to contact you.  Your browser may allow you to set a Do Not Track (DNT) signal indicating that you do not wish your online activity to be tracked. Currently, our system does not support and acts act on DNT signal headers that we may receive. However, the choices that we provide you concerning collection and use of your Personal Information will continue to operate as described in this Privacy Policy.

#### Children

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. We take kids' privacy seriously, and encourage parents to play an active role in their children's online experience at all times. If it is discovered that we have unintentionally collected information from a user under the age of 13, we will delete the child's information. 

#### Information You Provide Us

FOSI only collects personal information from you on a voluntary basis. When you submit personal information to FOSI, it will usually take the form of:

  1. Registration for our mailing list  

  2. Registration for our events
  3. Use of "Share" or "Tell-a-friend" features
  4. Customer or technical support inquiries  

  5. Participation in online surveys, polls or questionnaires  

#### The information we collect may include personal information such as your:

  1. name  

  2. email address  

  3. telephone number  

  4. shipping address  

Additionally, we and our third-party service providers may also collect other types of non-personal information (known as demographic information) such as your country, age or date of birth, gender, hobbies, occupation. This demographic information may be associated with your personal information. 

#### Information Collected Through Third Parties

In certain instances, we may collect information from you through our third-party service providers. FOSI, like many other website operators, uses Google Analytics for the purpose of analyzing our user base and improving the performance of our websites and services. If you wish to learn more about Google Analytics, including how to opt-out, please visit <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. 

We use MailChimp as a third-party email service provider, and may collect your IP address and location information from them. Additionally, your credit card information may be shared with us if you submit a donation to us via PayPal or register for one of our events through Eventbrite.

#### Information Collected Through Social Networking Sites

You also can engage with our content on or through third-party social networking sites, such as Facebook and Twitter (or third-party social media plug-ins and applications). When you engage with our content on or through third-party social networking sites, plug-ins and applications, you may allow us to have access to certain information from your social media profile (e.g., name, e-mail address, photo, gender, birthday, location, your list of friends, people you follow and/or who follow you, the posts or the 'likes' you make) to deliver the content or as part of the operation of the application. We may also obtain non-personally identifiable information (e.g., content viewed, game performance, high scores, and information about advertisements within the content you have been shown or may have clicked on,) from your interaction with our content.  

When you provide information from your social media account, it can help enable us to do things like (1) give you exclusive content, (2) personalize your online experience with us within and outside our websites (and/or applications), and (3) contact you through the social networking sites or directly by sending you the latest news, special offerings, and rewards. By doing so, you consent to the use of this information in accordance with our privacy policy. When you provide personal information to us through an application, on our sites, or on social networking sites, it may be publicly viewed by other members of these sites and we cannot prevent further use of the information by third parties. Through some social networking sites' privacy settings, you can control what data you share. For more information about how social networking sites handle your personal information, please refer to their privacy policies and terms of use.  

#### Information Collected Through Technology  

We collect information through technology to make our websites more interesting and useful to you. For example, when you visit our website, we collect your IP address. At times, we also use IP addresses to collect information regarding the frequency with which our guests visit various parts of our websites.

#### Cookies

Our websites also use cookies. Cookies are pieces of information that a website sends to your computer while you are viewing the website. We and other companies use cookies for a variety of purposes. For example, when you return to one of our websites after logging in, cookies provide information to the website so that the website will remember who you are. You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You can do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer or Firefox) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your settings. If you turn cookies off, you won't have access to many features that make your web experience smoother, like the features mentioned above, and some of our services may not function properly. By using our website you agree, and we will assume you consent, to receive cookies through our websites unless you change your browser settings to disable cookies. You can withdraw your permission to receive cookies at any time by changing your browser settings to disable cookies.  

Finally, once you've clicked on an advertisement or a third party link and have left our websites, our Privacy Policy no longer applies and you must read the privacy policy of the advertiser/third party to see how your personal information will be handled on its website.  

Please be sure to review our Cookie Policy at: https://www.fosi.org/cookie-policy/

Back to Top

###  Q3. How is your personally identifiable information used and shared?

Whatever the purpose may be, we will only collect information to the extent reasonably necessary to fulfill your requests and our legitimate business objectives.

#### FOSI Activities and Updates

Information collected from those who voluntarily submit it to us is used to provide services like newsletter subscriptions, updates on special events, and e-mail announcements of interest to our users. 

#### Blogs and Message Boards

If you register for access to our blogs or message boards, we will use your personal information to enable you to view and post messages on the boards. You should understand, however, that community forums, blogs, and message boards are tools that allow you to communicate with members of the online community. The information posted in these public areas can be collected and used by other people, so we highly suggest that you do not post any personal information you do not want publicly displayed or shared.

Should you wish to edit or remove a blog comment after you have posted it, you are able to do so by visiting the original post and clicking the “Edit” option underneath your post or by clicking the upside down arrow to the right of your post to select the “Delete” option.  Alternatively, you may contact us directly at [fosi@fosi.org](mailto:fosi@fosi.org) with your content or information removal request. 

Removal of this content or information from public view does not guarantee complete or comprehensive removal. After your removal request has been honored, we may retain copies of the content or information you have previously posted on our servers. We are not required to remove your posted content or information if it has been rendered anonymous or if we are required by law to retain it. Additionally, we do not have control over third parties (e.g., other users) who may have copied or reposted this information.

#### Operational Uses  

We may also use your personal information for other purposes such as "Operational Uses." For example, we may use your information to send you administrative communications either about your account with us or about features of our websites.  

We occasionally employ other companies to perform services necessary to our internal operations. For example, we have partnered with other companies to personalize our web pages, analyze customers' interaction with our website, and process consumer surveys. While providing their services, these companies may access your personally identifying information. These companies have agreed to securely store and maintain the personal information received from us.  

#### Aggregate Information  

Finally, we may take your personally identifiable information and make it non-personally identifiable. We do this either by combining it with information about other individuals (aggregating your information with information about other individuals), or by removing characteristics (e.g., your name) that make the information personally identifiable to you. This process is known as de-personalizing your information. Given the non-personal nature of this information, no restrictions apply under this Privacy Policy on our right to de-personalize your personal information. We may use de-personalized information in any way and share it with third parties without your consent.

#### Business Information  

For practical reasons, we treat personal information submitted to us in a business capacity different from information we receive in a non-business capacity. Personal information submitted to us in a business capacity (e.g. resumes) may be shared with third parties, depending on the nature of the inquiry.

#### Purchase or Sale of Businesses

From time to time, we may purchase a business or sell one or more of our businesses and your personally identifiable information may be transferred as a part of the purchase or sale. If we purchase a business, the personally identifiable information received with that business would be treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy, if it is practicable and permissible to do so. If we sell a business, we will include provisions in the selling contract requiring the purchaser to treat your personally identifiable information in the same way required by this Privacy Policy (including any amendments to this Privacy Policy). The provisions of this paragraph will also apply if we are sold as part of bankruptcy proceedings.  

#### Third Party Use  

Our company does not share and has not reserved the right to share personal or demographic information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes.  

 **Disclosures Required By Law and Disclosures to Help Protect the Security and Safety of Our Websites and Others**  

We will disclose personal information when we believe in good faith that disclosure is required by law (e.g., court order or subpoena) or help enforce:  

  1. our contest, sweepstakes, promotions, or game rules;  

  2. protect your safety or security, including the safety and security of your property; or  

  3. protect the safety and security of our websites or third parties.  

Back to Top

###  Q4. What choices do you have about the collection, use, and sharing of your personally identifiable information?

If you want to remove yourself from individual contests or promotions, or have any questions about any of our third-party service providers, please e-mail us at [fosi@fosi.org](mailto:fosi@fosi.org). If you would like to unsubscribe from receiving emails or newsletters from FOSI, simply click on the unsubscribe link in the email newsletter. In certain cases, we may still retain your information to resolve disputes, enforce our Terms of Use, or comply with legal requirements; in these instances, your personal information will be blocked from use for any other purpose.

Back to Top

###  Q5. What are your California Privacy Rights?

Since 2005, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits our customers who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. We do not share our customer’s personal information with unaffiliated third parties for their own direct marketing purposes. For inquiries regarding our disclosure policy, please write us:  

 _Family Online Safety Institute    
Attn.: Privacy Policy   
400 7th St., NW Suite 506  
Washington, D.C. 20004_ _  
_

Back to Top

###  Q6. What kinds of security measures do we take to safeguard your personally identifiable information?

The security and confidentiality of your information is extremely important to us. That's why we have technical, administrative and physical security measures in place to protect your personal information from unauthorized access and improper use. We also review our security procedures periodically to consider appropriate new technology and updated methods. But, despite our best efforts, no security measure is ever perfect or impenetrable. Specific security measures we currently implement to prevent unauthorized physical or electronic access to web users' personal and demographic information:

  * Web user data is stored behind a firewall.  

  * Data is stored in a secure physical environment (e.g. behind locked doors)  

  * Data is stored in a database accessible to authorized employees on a need-to-know basis only  

  * Users or employees must have a unique password before gaining access to user data  

  * We use standard encryption technology when transferring or receiving sensitive personal information like credit card numbers  

  * We maintain written security policies to which all employees must adhere.

Back to Top

###  Q7. How can you update your personal information and profile?

You can access and update or request the deletion of the contact information you gave us during registration (that is, your e-mail address or any other information that would directly enable us to contact you), by e-mailing us at [fosi@fosi.org](mailto:fosi@fosi.org).

Back to Top

###  Q8. How can you ask questions, or send us comments, about this Privacy Policy?

If you have questions or wish to send us comments about this Privacy Policy, please contact us with questions or comments at:

 _Family Online Safety Institute  
_ _Attn.: Privacy Policy  
_ _400 7th St., NW Suite 506  
_ _Washington, D.C. 20004_

As aforementioned, FOSI is a licensee of the ESRB's Privacy Certified Program. If you believe we have not responded to your privacy-related inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, please contact ESRB at <https://www.esrb.org/privacy/contact.jsp> or 

 _ESRB  
Attn: Privacy Certified Program  
420 Lexington Avenue, Suite 2024  
New York, NY 10170_  

Back to Top

###  Q9. How will you know if we amend this Privacy Policy?

We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make any material changes in how we collect, use, or share your personal information, we will send you a private message and prominently post a notice of the changes on the websites covered by this Privacy Policy. Any material changes to this Privacy Policy will be effective when posted, and your continued use of any of the websites covered by the Privacy Policy after the posting, will constitute your acceptance of and agreement to be bound by those changes.

Back to Top
